CURRICULUM VITAE

PRIMUS OCHIENG APAMO



PERSONAL INFORMATION

Cell: +254 700 129 491

Email primusochieng@uonbi.ac.ke

primusochieng@gmail.com/

primochieng@live.com/

Mailing Address: 100507 - 00101, Nairobi

Kenya.

PROFILE

Primus is the Programme Director of Oncology Postgraduate training at the University of Nairobi. He is both a lecturer and a consultant clinical oncologist at Kenyatta National Hospital. Prior to taking up this post, he had a placement at Christie Oncology NHS Trust (UK) to benchmark on Postgraduate medical education. He is currently taking fellowship training in advanced Radiotherapy namely Cyber knife, stereotactic radiotherapy, and interstitial brachytherapy in India. He has keen interest in research, and he is the principal site investigator of Unitid oncology clinical trial site at University of Nairobi. To achieve all these, he is keen on collaborating with various training centers in the developed world in areas of training, research, and skills development.

Signature



EDUCATION

Master of Medicine	/Fellowship in	Radiotherapy/	'Clinical Onco	logy
--------------------	----------------	---------------	----------------	------

2014 - 2018

University of Cape Town, South Africa.

Diploma in Health Systems Management

2006 -2007

Galilee College, Israel

Bachelor of Medicine & Surgery

1990 -1996

University of Nairobi, Kenya.

EXPERIENCE

Clinical fellowship

Ongoing

Medanta Medicity Hospital India

- Cyberknife simulation, treatment planning and treatment delivery
- Stereotactic Body radiotherapy Simulation treatment planning and treatment delivery
- Interstitial / Intervention brachytherapy in Gynecological tumors, Head and neck, GIT tumors and urologic tumors

Site principal investigator

March 2022 to date

University of Nairobi Institute of Tropical and infectious disease

- Supervise conducting include those delegated with trial activities.
- Conduct study in accordance with protocol.
- Satisfy and maintain adherence to local regulatory requirements.
- Ensure adequate enrollment and financial solvency.
- Maintain adequate training of site personnel.
- Ensure integrity of study data
- Protect the rights, safety and welfare of patients.
- Submit study documents adverse events progress reports, deviation from investigation plan.

Senior Research Fellow

November 2021

University of Nairobi Institute of Tropical and infectious disease

- Write and attract research grants to the University.
- Develop and mount training program.
- Setting up a clinical trial center.

Medical Education Placement

October 2019

Christie Oncology NHS Trust, Britain.

- Competency-based medical education for postgraduate oncology at the Fellow of Royal College of Radiology (FRCR) in Britain.
- Medical management of oncology patients, satellite clinics, MDT patient management.
- Collaboration in areas of research, networking, and skills transfer.

Consultant Clinical Oncologist

February 2019

Kenyatta National Hospital, Kenya.

- Provision of clinical care to cancer patients.
- Participating in the formulation of protocols and guidelines for cancer management.

Program coordinator & Lecturer,

November, 2019

Department of Diagnostic & Radiation Medicine.

University of Nairobi, Kenya

- Course coordination of the clinical oncology master's program.
- Lecturing and supervising master's Students in clinical oncology.
- Team leader at Multidisciplinary tumor boards and grand rounds.
- Mentoring master's students in clinical oncology
- Supervision of Master of Medicine Student thesis.
- Lecturing clinical oncology units to MMED students in surgical and non-surgical specialties

Registrar in Radiation Oncology

2014 -2018

Groote Schuur Hospital, South Africa

- Taking calls at the Emergency center & wards as per training requirements.
- Providing Oncology care under the supervision of consultants.

- Presenting cases in MDT and tumor boards.
- Administration of chemotherapy to both in and out-patients.
- Providing counseling and participating in other palliative care activities.

Medical Superintendent/ Site Doctor for phase III trial of Pyramax 2005-2008

Siaya District Hospital, Kenya.

- Clinical work as a medical officer.
- Responsible for the daily operations of the hospital.
- Supervision of junior doctors and other clinical staff.
- Ensuring the enforcement of standards and regulatory laws of the Ministry at the Hospital.
- Follow-up study -recruited patients.
- Ensuring that staff in the study adhere to study protocols.

Medical Officer

2004 - 2005

Siaya District Hospital, Kenya.

- Managing in-patients with surgical, medical, pediatric and gynecological complications.
- Carrying out surgical emergencies.
- Participating in medical legal issues such as performing post-mortems, testifying in Courts for Autopsies.

Clinical Services Manager

2001-2004

Metropolitan Hospital, Kenya.

- Managing in-patients with surgical, medical, pediatric and gynecological complications.
- Carrying out surgical emergencies.

Clinical Branch Manager

1998 -2001

Avenue Hospital, Industrial area, Kenya.

- Responsible for the daily operations of the branch.
- Supervision of junior doctors and other clinical staff.
- Ensuring the enforcement of standards and regulatory laws of the Ministry at the Hospital.
- Coordinating with the cashier to ensure that cash collections are banked on a daily basis.

Medical Officer (Internship)

1996 - 1997

Kenyatta National Hospital, Kenya

• Learning the ropes of Clinical work as a medical officer.

AWARDS AND HONORS

- Research Grant: COVID -19 Process improvements in Africa Funded by Pfizer
 Pharmaceuticals-2021
- Research Grant; CRTPA-KENYA Postgraduate research funds University of Nairobi
 2020 -2023
- Best Employee Award: Kenyatta National Hospital -2010
- Best Employee Award: Avenue Healthcare -1999

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

1. Cancer and COVID -19 experience at African Centers: Silver lining.

DOI 10 .1200/Go.20.00564 JCO Global Oncology No 7.

2. Impact of COVID 19 on cancer treatment delivery in sub-Saharan Africa Annals of Oncology Published September 2021

3. Clinical outcomes and barriers to cancer care delivery for patients with rectal cancer in Nairobi Kenya.

DO1 101200/JCO.2023.4 Suppl 17 41.04 -Suppl (Feb 01,2023)

<u>AUTHORSHIP</u>

Skill

 Chapter 27 of Non melanoma Skin cancer Essential for oncologist 2022 ISN 978100326017.

PROFFESSIONAL SKILLS

Organization Certificate: Basic Life Support Resuscitation Council of Kenya Certificate Advanced Pediatric Life Support Gertrude's Garden Children's Hospital

Certificate: Pediatric ART Management **NASCOP**

Christian Medical Association Certificate: Advanced Trauma Life Support

Certificate: Adults Retroviral Management NASCOP

FRCR (South Africa) Fellowship in Radiation Oncology

TRAININGS ATTENDED

 PYRAMAX R Pediatric and gynecological illnesses Meeting and Training: Sept 2006 – Dakar, Senegal

- Multidisciplinary Cancer Management Course (ASCO&KESHO): Feb 2009 Nairobi,
 Kenya
- Palliative Care Introductory Course: May 2009 Nairobi Kenya
- Regional (AFRA) Training course on PECT in Oncology: Oct 2011 Cairo, Egypt
- Roche Oncology Expert symposium: Sept 2012 Cape Town, South Africa.
- Regional (AFRA) Training Course on Evidence Based Brachytherapy: Oct 2012 –
 Harare, Zimbabwe.
- ESMO AFRICA: Oct 2016 Cape Town, South Africa
- Pediatric Brain Tumor Workshop; Nov 2017 -Cape Town, South Africa
- Pedagogy and Andragogy: May 2019 University of Nairobi, Nairobi, Kenya.
- IQVIA Africa Health Summit Nov 2022 Nairobi
- ICH GCP Training by IQVIA March 2023 Nairobi Kenya
- ESTROGEN ADVANCED BRACHYTHERAPY March 2023 Hyderabad India
- Elektra Master course in Head Neck and breast brachytherapy April 2023 Tata
 Memorial Hospital India
- Prostate Brachytherapy workshop June 2023 Hinduja Hospital India

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS & OTHER MEMBERSHIPS

- ASCO American Society of Clinical Oncology. 2010 to date
- KESHO Kenya Society of Hematology and Oncology. 2008 to date
- KMA –Kenya Medical Association of Kenya. 2000 to date
- SASCRO South African Society for Clinical and Radiation Oncologists. 2018 to date
- AFROG Association of African Radiation Oncologists. 2019 to date
- ESMO- European Society of Medical Oncology. 2016 to date
- HNS GEC ESTRO Working Group Member. 2019 to date

MINISTRY OF HEALTH KENYA ASSIGNMENTS

- Member of National Cancer Treatment Guideline in Kenya -2019
- Member of E-learning Childhood Cancer Guideline in Kenya -2021

- Member of Radiotherapy advisory Committee Kenya- 2020
- Member of Multidisciplinary Tumor board Meetings, Head and Neck, Gynae, Breast,
 Lung, Urology and Upper GI Tumors.
- Secretariat to National cancer Task force MOH Kenya 2021/2022

PRESENTATIONS

Managements of low-grade Glioma in Pediatrics.

Poster presentation at Pediatric Brain Tumor Workshop. Cape Town, 2009.

• Cancer Prevention Guidelines

KESHO Presentation Feb 2019 Kenya

Reirradiation in Nasopharyngeal tumors to full dose at Kenyatta National Hospital.

Presentation at AFROG meeting at Kenyatta National Hospital 2019

• Grand Round Presentation Oncology Training in Kenya.

Christie Oncology Centre, Manchester, United Kingdom Nov 2019

• Management of Radiation Toxicity in Head and Neck Cancers.

KESHO Symposium Nov 2020 Kenya

• Impact of COVID -19 on Cancer Care in KENYA:

Guest Speaker Mayo Clinic, USA Feb 2021

• European school of oncology Skin Academic meeting online

Challenges of palliating, inoperable squamous cell carcinoma of the scalp in a patient with Xeroderma pigmentosa in resource limited setting.

• Clinical Trials landscape in Africa with focus on Kenya

Roche sponsored meeting Jan 2023 Kenya

Challenges of radiotherapy treatment in Head and Neck in Kenya

Head and Neck Symposium Kenya March 2023 Kenya

REFEREES;

Dr Callen K Onyambu Chairman of Diagnostic Radiology and Radiation Medicine University of Nairobi P.O. Box19676-00202, Nairobi, Kenya. Telephone: +254 020 2724722 Email: callen.onyambu@uonbi.ac.ke

Kenneth W Merrel MD, MS Assistant Professor at Radiation Oncology Mayo Clinic College of Medicine 200 First STREET SW ROCHESTER MN 55905 merrellkenneth@mayo.edu

Prof Julius Oyugi Director UNITID Factuality of Health Sciences P.O.B ox 19676-00202, Nairobi, Kenya. Julius.oyugi9@gmail.com